最初  宇宙是一片黑暗
In the beginning, there was darkness,
紧接着一声巨响  混沌初开
and then, bang, giving birth
时间  空间和物质
to an endless, expanding existence
开始不断膨胀
of time, space, and matter.
每天  我们都在解密这神秘莫测
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking the mysterious,
彗星撞击木星
发现新行星
令人疯狂的极端之地
the mind-blowing, the deadly secrets
流星撞地球
宇宙
of a place we call the Universe.
它们是人类在外太空的眼和耳
They are humanity's eyes and ears in deep space,
探测火星上的平原  土星卫星上的间歇喷泉
exploring the plains of Mars, the geysers of Saturn's moon,
和遥远恒星炽烈的表面
and the blazing surfaces of distant stars.
他们就是空间探测器  机器人探测器
They are space probes: robotic explorers
现在是人类在星际间的化身
that are now humanity's interstellar avatars.
他们所能到达的地方和见到的事物
They can go places and see things
是我们在地球上永远到不了也看不到的
that we could never do from here on earth.
空间探测器分散分布在太阳系
Space probes fan out across the solar system,
传回的数据让我们对已知的事物有所改观
returning data that change everything we thought we knew.
如果我们能在银河系的其他地方找到生命的存在
If we could find indigenous life elsewhere in our galaxy,
这将是人类历史上最伟大的发现之一了
it would be one of the greatest discoveries in the history of humans.
探测器迎面撞击冰冷的彗星
Probes collide head-on into icy comets,
拍摄宇宙的边缘之地
photograph the edge of the universe itself,
甚至在其他星系中寻找行星
even seek planets in other solar systems.
我们处在一个探索发现类地行星的黄金时代
We're at a golden age in the search and discovery of earth-like planets.
通过揭示各种奥秘
A new generation of robotic explorers
新一代机器人探测器正在重新定义这个星系
is redefining the galaxy itself by unlocking secrets:
空间探测器的奥秘
secrets of the space probes.
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制&调校:无影  字幕来源:人人影视  招募Q号:76846146
宇
宙
空 间 探 测 器 的 奥 秘
第5季　第5集
此时此刻
At this very moment,
距地球数百万英里之外的地方
millions of miles from the earth,
人类正在取样  测量  摄影
human beings are sampling, measuring, photographing
甚至吸进另一个世界的尘埃和气体
and even sniffing the dust and gases of other worlds.
但不是亲身经历
But not in person.
宇宙的环境非常不利于人类生存
The environment of space is very hostile to people.
极端温度
It's got extremes of temperature,
艾米·美因茨
美国国家宇航局/喷气推进实验室
极端真空  高辐射区
extremes of vacuum, high radiation fields,
所有这一切都非常不适合人类居住
all kinds of things that are really inhospitable to human life.
机器人代替我们的眼和耳去执行任务
Our eyes and ears are robotic proxies sent on missions
探索太阳系甚至更远处的奥秘
to discover the secrets of our solar system and beyond.
它们是空间探测器
They are space probes
能在恶劣之境和危险之地生存
and they were built to survive the hostile atmospheres and perilous worlds
这是人类所办不到的
that mankind cannot.
我们的航空探测器能够在困境中生存
Our space missions are able to survive these difficult environments
所到之处  所做之事都是我们望尘莫及的
and they can go places and do things that we could never dream of without them.
一些探测器  如哈勃空间望远镜
Some probes, like the Hubble Space Telescope,
在地球轨道上自在漂浮  另外一些
float comfortably in earth's orbit, while others,
如2005年的"深度撞击号"  指定执行自杀性任务
like Deep Impact in 2005, are ordered on kamikaze missions
将人造卫星探测器直接撞向彗星
to smash satellite probes into comets.
还有一些用于行星探秘
Others are sent to uncover the secrets of planets
如火星  木星  土星  或其卫星
like Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, or their moons,
通过在轨道上进行图像分析
imaging and analyzing them from orbit
登陆进行地表探测或取样
and landing on their surfaces to explore or dig for samples.
探测器用来回答基本问题
Our probes are used to answer fundamental questions
包括行星的构成
about planetary composition,
凯文·P·格雷瑟尔
美国国家宇航局/喷气推进实验室
大气成分  地质情况  大气运动
atmospheric composition, geologic, atmospheric processes,
以及它们与地球的相似及不同之处
how are planets both similar to and different than earth
更为重要的问题是  有无生命存在
and the big-picture question: is there life?
寻找外星生命始于两千年前
The hunt for life on other worlds began over 2,000 years ago
那时希腊天文学家们开始关注行星
when Greek astronomers began gazing at planets.
21世纪  人类终于准备好去寻找外星生命
In the 21st century, humanity is finally poised to find it.
向太阳系甚至更远处发射探测器
Sending out probes into the solar system and even beyond,
是一项长期任务的一部分
it is part of a long-standing mission
我们不仅必须了解地球上的我们自己
we've had to understand, not just ourselves here on earth,
克利福德·约翰逊
南加利福尼亚大学
还必须了解太阳系中其他星球
but the rest of the solar system.
在某种程度上
And in some ways,
探索过程让我们对自己有了更多的了解
that quest helps us learn more about ourselves
比如人类起源这个话题
in terms of where we may have come from
是否有与地球上的环境类似
and whether there are any other examples
的其他地方
of the environment we see here on earth.
最近一次探索以超高分辨率的
The latest quest begins with an ultra-high-resolution
数字红外路线图为起点
digital infrared road map.
2009年12月14日
On December 14, 2009,
三角洲2号火箭向离地球300英里外的轨道
a Delta II Rocket delivered a small package into orbit
发射了一个小型探测器
300 miles above the earth.
它被称为"智慧号"
It's called W.I.S.E.,
将创建迄今为止最为精细的宇宙红外图像
and it's creating the most detailed infrared photograph of the universe to date.
"智慧号"是广范围红外线观测探测器
W.I.S.E. is the wide-field infrared survey explorer,
是个小体积望远镜
and it's a small-size telescope,
直径约为40公分
about 40 centimeters in diameter.
相当于我手臂下面这里的尺寸
So that would sort of fit under my arm here.
并且用于勘测整个太空的红外波段
And it's surveying the entire sky for infrared wavelengths.
探测距地球最近的星球
Everything from the earth's closest neighbors,
小行星  彗星
the asteroids and the comets,
甚至宇宙最远方的红外波段
to the most distant parts of the universe.
哈勃空间望远镜
Unlike the Hubble telescope
一般观测可见光到紫外光的波段
that generally images wavelengths, visible to ultraviolet light,
"智慧号"则勘测太空中的红外光
W.I.S.E. probes the universe using infrared light.
人类对于红外线的感觉是热
Human beings perceive infrared as heat.
阳光照在我们皮肤上产生的热感
When we feel the sun's warmth on our skin,
其实是来自于阳光中的红外线
what we're really sensing are the infrared rays coming from the sun.
我坐在这里就散发着红外线
I'm pouring out infrared light as I sit here,
我们可以利用红外线
and we can use infrared
来寻找类似温度的物体
to look for things that are sort of similar temperature,
例如  小行星
like, for example, asteroids.
我们还能利用红外线来寻找整个宇宙中
We can also use infrared to look for the most distant galaxies
最遥远的星系
in the entire universe.
这些遥远的星系很多都不能被可见光谱勘测到
Many of these distant galaxies can't be perceived in the visible light spectrum.
"智慧号"红外望远镜成了一副魔力眼镜
The W.I.S.E. infrared telescope becomes like a magic set of glasses.
就像消防员用红外护目镜
So, just like a firefighter uses infrared goggles
在着火的大楼里透过烟雾救人
to look through smoke in a burning building to find people,
天文学家用红外线能透过尘云
astronomers can use infrared to see through dust clouds
寻找其内部正在形成的恒星
to look for forming stars in their cores.
但是呈现这些隐藏的热源信号
But revealing these hidden heat signatures
首先需要一个深冷环境
first requires an extreme deep freeze.
"智慧号"的四百万像素望远镜
W.I.S.E.'s 4 million-pixel telescope
只能拍摄比其温度低的物体的红外图像
can only photograph infrared images if the telescope is colder than the objects it searches for.
所以  我们需要确保
So, we need to make sure
没有因为我们望远镜的热度而产生的盲点
that we're not blinded by the heat of our own telescope.
我们在"智慧号"上用了一箱固态氢
On W.I.S.E., we use a tank of solid hydrogen
它在接近绝对零度下凝固
that's frozen near absolute zero,
这样就能冷却我们的望远镜和设备
and this keeps our telescope and our instrument cold.
就像个装满冰的冷却器
Just like a cooler full of ice,
"智慧号"上的固态氢
the frozen hydrogen on board W.I.S.E.
最终将升华消失
is eventually going to sublimate away.
当我们用完所有的固态氢时
When we run out of all of the hydrogen ice,
望远镜和设备将变热
the telescope and the instrument will warm up to the point that
直至我们无法勘测
we'll no longer be able to see.
冷却到零下447华氏度[-266摄氏度]
Frozen to minus 447 degrees Fahrenheit,
固态氢只能持续十个月
the hydrogen can only last for about 10 months.
到那时  大约150万张图像
By that time, some 1.5 million photographs
将组成一幅巨大的太空合成图
will create a giant composite picture of the heavens:
一本揭示了新世界的宇宙地图集
a cosmic road atlas that can reveal new worlds
供未来的空间探测器设立目标
for future space probes to target,
很可能是探测有外星生命的世界
potentially, worlds with alien life forms.
但是若要找距地球好几光年的外星生命
But if we are to find alien life many light-years from earth,
我们需要一条关键线索来指引我们
we'll need a critical clue to lead us there.
在地球上  那条线索就是覆盖星球面积71%的水
On earth, that clue covers 71% of our planet: Water.
我们对寻找液态水的兴趣主要在于
One of the main reasons we're interested in finding
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
美国加州大学伯克利分校
我们真的想知道在
liquid water is that we really would like to know,
太阳系的其他地方是否存在生命
is there life elsewhere in the solar system?
众所周知  地球上的生命需要水来维持
Life on Earth, as we know it, needs water to survive.
需要水来形成生命
It needs water to form.
我们希冀在其他星球发现生命
We hope to find life elsewhere,
作为生命存在的指路明灯  首先需要找的
and a signpost for life might be first finding a place
或许就是有水  液态水
where there's water, liquid water.
纵贯人类历史
Throughout human history,
尚未有证据指出宇宙中
there was no proof that liquid water existed
除地球外还有地方存在液态水
anywhere else in the universe besides Earth,
直至97年一台先进的空间探测器到达土星
until a sophisticated space probe arrived
执行探索任务才颠覆了我们的认知
on a mission of discovery to the planet Saturn in 1997.
卡西尼号耗时4年  行程4亿英里
Cassini traveled 400 million miles and took four years
才到达土星  开始历时数年的探测行动
to begin a multi-year spy mission
以揭示土星的奥秘
to uncover the secrets of Saturn.
卡西尼号探测器前往土星
When the Cassini probe got to Saturn,
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯天文台
它不仅只是研究该行星及其所有的卫星
not only did it study all the moons and the planet in particular,
而且还会脱离飞船  变换轨道
but then it went out of the plane, changed its orbit,
由上至下的观测土星环
and could look down on the Rings.
其中一环尤其吸引卡西尼号科学家的注意
One ring in particular attracted Cassini scientists.
我们知道土星最外环  E环
We knew that Saturn's outermost ring, the "E" Ring,
是由极其细小的微米级冰粒组成
was made of very small micron-sized ice particles.
微米级的冰粒子在太空中无法长存
Micron-sized ice particles don't last long in space.
我们知道在土星系统中
We knew there was a source of stuff in the Saturn system
必定存在形成E环的供源
that was creating the "E" Ring.
我们当时猜测是土卫二
We guessed it was Enceladus.
当卡西尼号接近土卫二时
When Cassini approached the moon, Enceladus,
目击了一种宇宙现象  证实了水
it witnessed a cosmic phenomenon and confirmed that water
的确同样是另外一个世界的关键成分
was indeed a key ingredient on another world.
卡西尼号宇宙飞船发现
The Cassini spacecraft has detected water
土卫二地表下存在水
under the surface of Enceladus,
它观测到从土卫二
and the way it was detected was that these geysers
地表裂隙中喷射出间歇泉
are coming out from fissures in the cracked surface of Enceladus,
泉水进入土卫二外部寒冷的空间环境时凝结成冰
and the water freezes as it comes out into the cold space surrounding Enceladus.
源源不断的冰粒形成了土星的E环
The constant stream of water ice particles feeds Saturn's "E" Ring,
它提醒了我们如果在太阳系内
An icy reminder that if liquid water exists
遥远的星球上存在液态水的话
on remote planets in our own Solar system,
那么在宇宙的其他地方也会有的
it might be found elsewhere in the universe.
然而卡西尼号对水源的搜寻尚未结束
But Cassini's hunt for liquids wasn't over.
它还将利用其灵敏的仪器
it would have to use its sensitive instruments
穿透土星系统内的其他大气层
to penetrate other atmospheres of the Saturnian system.
卡西尼宇宙飞船携带了12组科学仪器
The Cassini spacecraft has 12 science instruments.
其中4组是我们所说的光学遥感仪器
Four of them are what we call optical remote-sensing instruments.
它们观测的波长带等同或稍宽于人类肉眼
They see in the wavelength of band that humans see or just outside of it.
宇宙飞船安装的滤镜可以穿透
The spacecraft has filters that are designed to peer
层层迷雾探测掩盖下的地表
through that haze and see through to the surface below.
卡西尼号内的仪器
Cassini's instruments are designed
利用各种工具来收集情报信息
to gather intelligence with different tools,
与人类运用自身的各种感官大同小异
much the same way that humans use our different senses.
卡西尼的直接遥感器
Cassini's direct and remote sensors
首先开始研究的是土星的泰坦卫星
first began studying Saturn's moon, Titan,
有人相信这里存在着液态水
a place that some believed could contain liquid water.
泰坦比水星还要巨大
Titan is bigger than the planet Mercury,
有浓密的大气层
with a dense atmosphere,
甚至比地球的大气层还要浓厚
thicker than even the earth's atmosphere.
当1980年旅行者号空间探测器
In 1980, when the Voyager space probe flew by on its way
在去往太阳系外层途径此地时
to the outer solar system,
拍摄的照片暗示了存在着另一种液体现象
its photographs hinted at another liquid phenomenon.
旅行者号宇宙飞船向我们展示了
What the voyager spacecraft
它的大气层里充满了碳氢化合物
told us is that that atmosphere is filled with hydrocarbons...
甲烷  乙烷  产生了浓厚的光化雾霾
Methane, ethane, that create a thick photochemical haze.
旅行者号飞船无法看透那层雾霾
The voyager spacecraft couldn't see through that haze.
当25年后卡西尼号开始研究泰坦时
When Cassini began studying Titan 25 years later,
它还发射了颗名为惠更斯的卫星监控探测器
it also launched a satellite spy probe called Huygens.
该探测器穿过泰坦的碳氢大气层
the probe penetrated the thick hydrocarbon atmosphere
在地表着陆
and landed on Titan's surface.
卡西尼及其着陆器的发现令人震惊
What Cassini and its lander found was shocking.
最初  卡西尼和惠更斯观测到了
Very early on, Cassini and Huygens had seen hints
泰坦地表液体存在的细微迹象
of the evidence of fluids on the surface of Titan.
最终  它们发现了碳氢化合物
Eventually, they found hydrocarbons.
找到了碳氢湖  有些比五大湖还宽广
They found hydrocarbon lakes, some larger than the Great Lakes.
这是首次在太阳系内地球以外
These are the first open bodies of fluids
发现露天的液体
found in the Solar system outside of Earth.
典型的类地暴风雨使得湖水充盈
The lakes are filled by classic earth-like rainstorms.
然而在泰坦  雨滴并非是水
But on Titan, the raindrops are not H2O,
而是缓缓而下液态甲烷
but slow-falling liquid methane.
地球上的甲烷大都处于气体状态
A lot of the methane on Earth is in the gaseous state.
称为天然气  其实是源自腐烂的有机体
it's called natural gas, in fact, and it comes from decaying organisms.
有机体不停的分解  形成天然气
And they're still decomposing and they form this natural gas,
成为地球上可以使用的燃料
which we can use as a fuel here on Earth.
泰坦液态甲烷甚至能养育简单的生命体
Titan's liquid methane world could even harbor simple life forms,
就像在地球深海发现的单细胞生命
much like the single-celled life found in the depths of Earth's oceans.
那里存在的种种可能真是让人兴奋不已
So there's a lot of excitement about the possibilities that could be out there.
远方的行星系统是活跃的  有趣的
Planetary systems out there are active, interesting,
包罗万象的  生命的形式同样多姿多彩
and very varied, and we know that life can take many different forms.
或许能在遥远的围绕者其他恒星运转的
Life might be found on distant planets
星球上发现生命
orbiting other stars.
问题是如何到达彼方
The problem is getting there.
而新研制的超级引擎利用其类似
But a new super engine with a propulsion system similar
微波技术的推进系统
to microwave oven technology
正随时准备为深入外太空之旅推波助澜
is preparing to turbocharge deep space travel.
空间探测器能无畏的前往人类未履之地
Space probes can boldly go where no human has gone before.
然而数十年来
But for decades,
科学家一直与一个严酷的现实抗争
scientists have wrestled with a harsh reality:
空间探测器也会出师未捷
Space probes can fail.
每一次的成功  都建立在半个世纪以来
Every one that succeeds is built upon a half century
失败的任务和破灭的梦想之上
of failed missions and shattered dreams.
太空探测史从20世纪60年代开始
The history begins in the 1960s
美国宇航局首次尝试前往地球最近的邻居
with NASA's first attempts to reach Earth's nearest neighbors.
首批徘徊者号探测器是用于拍摄
Our first Ranger probes were designed to take images
月球以及硬着陆前的路线
of the Moon and a route to smashing into the Moon.
最初的6枚探测器完全偏离了月球
And our first six rangers missed the moon entirely,
凯文·P·格拉齐尔
美国航天航空局/喷气推进实验室
但是我们很快就吸取了教训
but we learn quickly.
徘徊者号探测器失败后数月
And a few months after the Ranger probes,
我们成功的发射了太空船飞过金星
we sent a successful spacecraft to fly past Venus.
1962年美国探测器
In 1962, the American probe,
水手2号是首个飞经金星的太空船
Mariner 2 Is the first spacecraft to fly past Venus.
它揭示了我们最近的邻居跟我们截然不同
It reports that our nearest neighbor is no place like home.
我们曾以为金星与地球如同孪生姐妹
We used to think that Venus might be like a twin sister of Earth
有着炎热潮湿的丛林
with hot steamy jungles.
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
美国加州大学伯克利分校
然而空间探测器告诉我们
Well, the space probes taught us that,
抱歉  金星有着天壤之别
sorry, Venus isn't like that.
美国宇航局的探测器证实金星太炎热了
The NASA probe proves that Venus is too hot
其气压太大无法承载任何生命
and its pressure is too great to support any life.
然而1970年首个登陆金星的探测器
But in 1970, the first probe to land
却并非来自美国  而是来自苏联
on the planet isn't American, but Soviet.
金星探测器有个内壳
The Venera probes had an inner shell,
钛金属构成的内舱非常牢固
an inner hull of titanium that was tough.
能在一段时间内经受住
It could withstand, at least for a while,
金星地表毁灭性压力和酷热
The crushing pressure and the intense heat of the Venus surface.
因此早期抵达金星的探测器在
So the early probes to Venus got destroyed
仅仅半小时不足一小时内被摧毁了
in just half an hour or under an hour.
在被气压碾碎前
They were able to take data
它们只能提供短时间的数据
for only a short amount of time before they got crushed.
但探测器在损坏前
But the data sent back
送回的数据准确而惊人
before Venera's destruction is precise and surprising.
金星的表面如同地狱
Conditions on the surface of Venus are hellish.
温度大约为华氏860度[460摄氏度]
The temperature is about 860 degrees Fahrenheit.
温度相当高
That's really, really high.
煮沸的开水仅有华氏212度
I mean the boiling point of water is 212 degrees
铅熔化的温度亦稍稍低于860度
and lead melts at a temperature slightly lower that 860.
所以如果你把铅放到金星表面
So, you'd have molten lead on the surface of Venus
就会的到熔融的铅
if you had lead there.
真是个恶劣的环境
It's a really bad place to be.
金星是探索科学家的极端环境试验场
Venus is an extreme training ground for probe scientists.
但还有一个更远大
But there is a more distant
更艰巨的目标
and difficult goal,
还有一种星的极端环境比金星更具破坏力
One whose extremes are even more destructive than Venus:
带外行星
the Outer Planets.
带外行星:  木星  土星  天王星  海王星和冥王星
仅有大型火箭不足以还到达那里
And getting there requires more than just a big rocket.
空间探测器的最大问题之一
One of the biggest problems with space probes
是拥有足以飞抵目的地的的燃料
is having enough fuel to get where you're going.
你发射火箭  花费很多燃料
If you do a rocket burn, you burn a lot of fuel.
特拉维斯·斯·泰勒
物理学家
保持一组火箭发射器运转
And if you keep doing a bunch of rocket burns,
会使你用尽燃料
you're gonna run out of fuel,
你的探测器就无用了
and then your probe is dead.
但存在一个解决方法
But there is a solution
利用宇宙结构  万有引力
built into the fabric of the cosmos: gravity.
六十年代早期  研究发现
In the early '60s, it was discovered
人们可以利用行星的引力
that we can use the gravity of the planets
来辅助航天器
to assist a spacecraft,
使其加速
to speed it up to fling it
将其送入外太阳系
further out into the solar system.
这开辟了对于外太阳系的探索
That opened up the outer solar system to exploration.
这项技术被称为  重力助推
The technique is called gravity assist,
是一个运用行星体的
a virtual engine that harnesses
巨大万有引力的虚拟引擎
the immense gravity of planetary bodies
在预定轨道上对航天器进行助推
to assist a spacecraft on a planned trajectory.
打棒球与借助重力的过程颇似
Hitting a baseball is a lot like a gravitational assist.
空间探测器到达一颗行星附近
The space probe comes into a planet,
被其引力捕获
it gets caught by the gravity
改变自己的方向
and redirected in another direction,
就像用球棒击打棒球
just like hitting a baseball with a bat
引导球转向其他方向
and it directs the baseball in another direction.
当球棒撞击棒球
When the bat collides with the baseball,
它就改变了棒球的运动方向
it changes the baseball's direction of motion
并且推动棒球
and it can propel that baseball
达到比撞击前更快的速度
with a much greater speed than what it originally had.
通过利用行星的引力
By harnessing the gravitational pull of planets,
美国宇航局可以将探测器送出驻留轨道
NASA has been able to hit probes out of the park
送至外行星
and to the Outer Planets.
卡西尼号太空船的本垒打
Cassini's home-run journey
飞跃了一亿七千万英里
covered 170 million miles
到达土卫泰坦的甲烷湖泊
to the methane lakes of Saturn's moon, Titan.
离开了重力助推  这艘在地球上
Without those gravity assists, this spacecraft,
重十二吨的航天器
which weighs 12 tons in earth's gravity,
是不可能到达外太阳系的
never would have made it to the outer solar system.
我们没有足以直接
We don't have a booster big enough
发送将它到土星的助推器
to send it to Saturn directly.
如果没有内行星的引力
We would not have explored Saturn
我们不能探索土星
were it not for the gravity of the inner planets.
现在  二十一世纪的空间探索
Now, 21st century space exploration
准备派遣探测器
is poised to send probes
到外行星以外的遥远恒星
beyond the outer planets to distant stars.
但重力助推
But gravity assist
不足以令我们到达那里
doesn't have the power to get us there.
进入深空探测看起来
Traveling into deep space requires propulsion
显然需要科幻小说中的动力
that seems to come straight out of science fiction:
离子推进器
the ion drive.
离子引擎就像一个小型直线加速器
Ion engines are like a mini linear accelerator.
你向后加速离子
You accelerate ions out the back,
航天器飞向相反的方向
the spacecraft goes the opposite direction.
离子引擎的推力  非常非常小
That ion engine has very, very low thrust,
但它一次可以运转数月  并且最终
but it operates for months at a time, and eventually,
使航天器的速度越行越快
gets the spacecraft up to faster and faster speeds.
离子引擎通过诸如氙气的惰性气体
The ion engine replaces the chemical fuel
取代了化学燃料
with an inert gas like xenon.
氙气提供了电荷  或称电离
The xenon is given an electrical charge, or ionized.
之后电子场加速离子
An electric field then accelerates the ions
离子从航天器后端飞出
out the back of the spacecraft,
推动航天器前进
propelling it forward.
离子推进器和大多数火箭引擎不同
Ion propulsion is not like most rocket engines.
一个普通化学火箭引擎推动自己的方式
A standard chemical rocket engine propels itself
像一把双管十二毫米口径猎枪
like a double-barreled 12-gauge shotgun.
猎枪实际上就是一个化学推力引擎
This shotgun is actually a chemical rocket engine,
和航天飞机的主发动机很像
just like the space shuttle main engines.
我坐在地球上的一辆小车上
I'm sitting on earth on a dolly track.
问题是  猎枪能否提供
So the question is, is there enough thrust
足以克服轮子和轨道间
from the shotgun to overcome
的摩擦力的推力呢
the friction between the wheels and the track?
单枪射击可以使小车移动六英尺
A single blast moves the dolly about six inches.
第二枪使运动状态持续
A second blast keeps the momentum going.
现在  用一个较小的武器
But now, replace the big double-barrel shotgun
替换大型双管猎枪
with a smaller weapon.
现在我拿着雷帽弹步枪
Now, I have a .22 rifle.
这和猎枪有些许区别
It's a little different than the shotgun.
猎枪以一个相当温和的速度
The shotgun shot many pellets out
射出许多子弹
at a fairly moderate velocity.
步枪高速射击出
The rifle shoots a small pellet out
一颗很小的子弹
at very high velocity.
区别就是
Now, the difference is that
这把更像离子引擎
this is more like an ion engine.
雷帽弹的反冲使小车移动了不到一英寸
The .22 recoil moves the dolly less than an inch.
连发射击使他移动了稍多一点
Multiple shots move it slightly more.
但如果我们身处太空中
But if we were in space,
雷帽弹就会像离子引擎
the .22 would be just like the ion engine.
它会开始慢慢推动我们
It would start pushing us slowly
最终使我们
and eventually build up,
达到一个很高的速度
till we reached a really high velocity.
通过微小推力不断汇集变大
By compounding tiny thrusts through the vast,
在无摩擦力的太空深处
frictionless depths of space,
离子引擎可以推动探测器数年
the ion engine can propel a probe for years.
加拿大理论天体物理研究所二次太空着陆计划
这项技术意味着
The technology could mean the end
大型火箭推进器在空间探测上应用的终结
for massive rocket boosters in space probe travel.
化学燃料存在问题
Chemical fuels are a problem
因为它们很低效
because they're pretty inefficient.
它们很重  体积很大
They weigh a lot. They have a lot of mass.
并且你需要把它们运到太空
And you have to transport all that stuff out there,
这意味着发射宇宙飞船的火箭
and that means the rockets that launch the spacecraft
需要更多能量  也更昂贵
have to be even more powerful, even more expensive.
轻量级离子引擎
Lightweight ion engines
已经通过了外太空试验
have already passed the test in outer space.
他们在九十年代末
They powered the deep space 1 probe
推助了深空一号探测器
in the late 1990s,
并在最近推动了日本宇宙航空研究开发机构
and recently propelled the probe, Hayabusa,
研制的隼鸟号号探测器
of the Japanese aerospace exploration agency
帮助它着陆到一个小行星
and helped it land on an asteroid.
离子引擎会彻底
Ion engines will completely
改变深空探索
change deep-space exploration
因为我们不需要很多燃料
because we can go a lot more places
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯观察员
就可以到达更多的地方
without having to carry a lot of fuel.
并且最终  我们可能以更快的速度达到那里
And we can get there, in the end, faster,
这取决于我们要去哪儿
depending on where it is we're going.
我们可能会去的地方之一
One of the places we may be going
是我们的邻近行星
is our planetary neighbor.
目前  欧洲航天局的火星快车探测器
Currently, the European space agency's mars express probe
保持了六个月从地球到达火星的速度冠军
holds the Earth-to-Mars speed title at six months,
但一个先进的离子引擎
but one advanced ion engine
有望打破这个纪录
is expected to shatter that record.
离子引擎可以使到火星的时间
An ion engine could cut the travel time to Mars
缩短至数周
down to just a mere few weeks.
五周到达火星仅仅是一个开始
Five weeks to Mars is only the beginning.
离子驱动器下一步将加快它的速度一百倍
The next step in ion drives will amp up its speed as much as 100 times faster.
这被称为Vasimr
It's called Vasimr,
可变比脉冲等离子体火箭的缩写
an acronym for variable specific impulse magneto-plasma rocket.
等离子体火箭的离子引擎增添了
Vasimr's ion engine gets an added
射频发生器和二级推进器
radio frequency generator and a second stage.
很重要的一点是它的工作原理有点像微波炉
One of the key things is it works kind of like a microwave oven.
微波炉发出电磁波
Just like a microwave beams electromagnetic energy
来加热食物
into the food to superheat it.
等离子体被加热后
As the plasma gets superheated,
它获得了多得多的能量
then it's got way more energy,
加热过的等离子体贮存在
It's got this really strong magnetic field that takes
探测器的很强的磁场中
that superheated plasma
并以极快的速度从其尾部喷射出来
And shoots it out the back end at really high velocities.
离子能够被加热到大约一百万度
The ions can be superheated to about one million degrees.
那足以将一个探测器送到我们太阳系之外很远
That's enough to send a probe far beyond our solar system.
随着火箭技术的发展
As rocket technology advances,
深空探索的大门正在打开
the gates of deep space are swinging open to exploration.
我们需要的只是目的地
All we need is a destination.
一个空间探测器此刻
One space probe is right now
正在宇宙中仔细寻找那个目的地
scanning the heavens for that destination:
一个新的地球  很有可能一种新的生命形式
a new earth, and possibly a new form of life.
空间探测器正站在天文学最古老追求之一的最前沿
Space probes are on the cutting edge of one of astronomy's oldest quests:
寻找另一个地球
the search for another earth.
现在  新一代的机器人探测器
Now, a new generation of robotic explorers
找到了太阳系外行星的证据
seeks evidence of extrasolar planets.
我们正在寻找它们
And we're finding them.
太阳系外行星简单来说
An extrasolar planet is simply
杰佛里·马尔西
美国加州大学伯克利分校
就是一颗绕另一颗恒星运转的行星
a planet that orbits another star.
我们太阳系有八大行星
We have eight major planets orbiting our sun,
而太阳是一颗典型的恒星
and our sun is a typical star.
几个世纪以来一直存在的一个问题是
And so a question that has loomed for centuries is
是否有行星围绕我们在夜空中看到的星星运转
whether there are planets that orbit the stars that we see at night.
自伽利略时代开始
Since the days of Galileo,
科学家们就相信在天空中的亿万颗星中
scientists have believed there must be other planets
一定存在其他行星
among the billions of stars in the sky.
但对太阳系外行星的探寻
But the quest for extrasolar or exoplanets
直到伽利略之后四百年才得以成功
wasn't successful until 400 years after Galileo.
一九九五年  在仅仅离地球五十光年的
In 1995, in the Pegasus constellation,
飞马星座
just 50 light-years from earth,
科学家们发现了第一颗真正的
Scientists discovered the first true
太阳系外行星  飞马座51b
extrasolar planet, 51 Pegasi b.
它仅仅是通过间接的线索发现的
It was found only through indirect clues.
我们只有通过一种"恒星摇摆法"
We were only being able to find these extrasolar planets
特拉维斯·S·泰勒
物理学家
才能找到这些太阳系外行星
using a technique called star wobble.
如果有一颗像木星一样的大行星存在
If you have a big planet like a Jupiter out there,
它会引起恒星的运动出现摇摆
it would cause the star's motion to wobble.
但你不能直接说它就在那里
But you couldn't really sort of directly tell it was there.
也称为多普勒效应
Also called the Doppler effect,
摇摆是通过望远镜发现的
The wobble is observed through a telescope.
如果恒星的光波有规律地
If the star's light regularly shifts
反复发生红移和蓝移
toward red or blue wavelengths and then back again,
那么围绕其运行的行星一定是引起光波偏移的原因
Then an orbiting planet must be causing the light to shift.
在过去的十多年  天文学家很幸运地
In the last decade or so, astronomers have been extremely lucky
发现了围绕其他恒星运行的上百颗行星
to find hundreds of planets around other stars.
但我们发现的行星是巨行星
But the planets we've been finding are the large ones:
像木星  土星和海王星那种
the Jupiters, the Saturns, some Neptunes.
我们还不能够发现类似地球大小的行星
We have not been able to find the earth-like planets,
如果它们存在的话
if they're out there.
人类已经发现了数百颗太阳系外行星
There are now hundreds of verified extrasolar planets.
但它们中存在离地球足够近可以供人类探索的吗
But are any of these planets close enough for mankind to explore?
来自宾夕法尼亚州伊利的安娜贝尔·C
That's what Annabelle C. From Erie, Pennsylvania,
向《宇宙解密》这样问道
wanted to "Ask the universe," when she texted us...
利用当今最先进的推进系统
How long would it take for a space probe reach the nearest explanet?
空间探测器要花多久才能到达最近的系外行星
Using theest propulsion available today?
安娜贝尔  很有意思的问题
Annabelle, that's a really interesting question,
而事实上  没有既定的答案
And, in fact, there's no set answer.
使用今天的技术
Using today's technology,
空间探测器花大约十万年才能到达另一颗恒星
A space probe could reach another star in about 100,000 years.
已知最近的太阳系外行星距地球10.5光年
The nearest known exoplanet is about 10 1/2 light-years away,
但有可能存在离地球更近的
But there might be a more nearby one,
或者我们可以在不久的将来改进推进技术
or we might improve space propulsion technology in the near future.
所以在相对不久的将来  也许我们能够
So maybe we could get that down to about 10,000 years
把时间缩短到大约一万年
in the relatively near future,
但对于现在来说  五万到二十万年
But something like 50,000 to 200,000 years
是一个比较好的答案
is a good answer for right now.
寻找类地行星意味着到宇宙更深处探索
Finding the earth-like planets means looking deeper into the cosmos,
去寻找更模糊和更遥远的恒星
at dimmer and more distant stars.
一种革命性的观察遥远恒星的技术
A revolutionary method of watching these dim stars
有可能会很快找出第一颗类地行星
could soon pinpoint the first new earth.
这种技术被称为凌日法
It's called the transit technique,
这种技术在行星绕过
and it offers a dead giveaway that an orbiting planet
我们视角下的恒星盘面时发现行星
is crossing between the star and our viewpoint from earth.
我们假设这个反射镜是恒星的盘面
So, let's imagine this reflector is like the face of a star
而在反射镜前面飞行的昆虫就像那颗行星
and a bug flying in front of that reflector is like the planet.
随着虫子围绕着反射镜前飞过时
As the bug goes in front of and around this reflector,
它会挡住反射镜一部分的光
it will block a little bit of the light from the reflector,
就同一颗行星运转时经过
just as would happen when a planet crosses
恒星前面时发生的情况一样
in front of a sun-like star.
光的减弱程度
The amount of dimming
往往小于恒星发出光强度的千分之一
is often less than 1/10 of 1% of the star's light output.
很难注意到  但对于一个在宇宙中探索的
Barely noticeable, but it's more than enough
拥有千里眼的空间探测器来说已经很足够了
for one far-sighted space probe that's now scouting the cosmos.
我们很想知道宇宙中是否存在一颗
We'd love to know if there's another earth-like planet
艾米·美因茨
美国国家宇航局/喷气推进实验室
类似地球的行星  如果有的话
out there somewhere, and the Kepler mission
开普勒计划大有可能找到它
has a good chance of being able to see it if there is one.
卡普勒号宇宙探测器是
The Kepler space probe is the powerful eye
科学家们用以发现类地行星的强有力工具
scientists will use to find the earth-like planets,
如谚语说的大海捞针
the proverbial needles in the haystack.
探测器的望远镜使用九千五百万像素的摄像机
The probe's telescope is using a 95-megapixel camera
来观察经过的行星
to watch for the transiting planets.
开普勒计划用所谓的"凌日法"
The Kepler mission is using the so-called transit technique
来寻找新的太阳系外行星
to search for new extrasolar planets.
使用凌日法
With the transit technique,
开普勒号探测器能够观察成千上万的恒星
Kepler is watching thousands of stars,
捕捉它们在行星经过时
Waiting for their light to slightly dim
亮度的轻微减弱
When a planet passes in front of the star.
银河系中有几十亿颗恒星
The milky way is composed of billions of stars,
也可能有几十亿颗类地行星
And potentially, billions of earth-like planets.
能都找到一颗类地行星
The odds of finding one earth
围绕某颗恒星运转的几率很低
orbiting one particular star are very low.
所以  开普勒会同时日夜不停地
So, Kepler will train its unblinking eye
观测数千颗恒星
on many thousands of stars at the same time.
我这有张光盘用来代表一个行星系
Here I have a DVD to represent a planetary system
其恒星在中间  一颗行星在外围绕它运转
with the star in the center and a planet going around the outside,
当然  大部分时间
And of course, most of the time,
该行星系同我们的视线平行
the planetary system is tilted to our line of sight.
所以随着行星的运转
And so, as the planet goes around,
它永远不会经过恒星前面  挡住星光
it never crosses in front of the star, blocking the starlight.
但如果我们幸运的话
But if we're lucky,
能够看到行星的轨道面
and the orbital plane of the planet is seen edge on,
当行星运转经过恒星前面时
then the planet crosses in front of the star,
挡住了部分光线  使恒星变得暗淡
blocking some of the starlight, and dimming the star.
所以  你得观察数万
And so, you have to be watching
甚至数十万的恒星
tens or even hundreds of thousands of stars
才能有幸捕捉到一些行星
to be lucky enough to catch a few planets
刚好运行在恒星前面
that happen to cross right in front of the star.
全世界在等待的同时  开普勒号探测器
As the world waits, kepler watches
每时每刻都在关注着遥远的恒星
the distant stars moment by moment.
但如果它真的找到一颗新的地球
But if it does find a new earth,
我们能够真正意义上地发现什么呢
What can we actually find out about it?
它看上去会像什么
What will it look like?
那里会有生命吗
Could there be life?
一旦开普勒发现像地球一样的行星
Once Kepler finds earth-like planets,
我非常肯定它会发现的
and I'm fairly sure it will be successful,
下一步就是
the next thing will be
试图分析来自那颗行星的光
to try to analyze the light from that planet.
这个地球上有哪些化学成分
What's the chemical composition of this earth?
它有含氧的大气层吗
Does it have an oxygen atmosphere
还是只有二氧化碳或甲烷
Or is it just carbon dioxide or methane?
这颗行星有大陆和海洋吗  表面有水吗
Does the planet have continents and oceans, water on the surface?
目前我们还没有这样的技术
Currently, we don't have the technology
可以分析遥远的类地球行星的大气层
to analyze the atmosphere of a distant earth-like planet.
但是那种情况就要改变了
But that's about to change.
2015年  詹姆斯·韦伯空间望远镜
In 2015, the James Webb space telescope will offer four times
将提供四倍于哈勃空间望远镜的成像能力
the imaging capability of the Hubble space telescope.
它将令科学家们可以观察位于
It will allow scientists to observe tiny molecules
类地球行星的大气层中的微小的分子
in the atmospheres of an earth-like planet
它距离地球可能有数千光年
That is potentially thousands of light-years from the earth.
所以我们正处于探索和发现
So we're at a golden age
类地球行星的黄金年代
in the search and discovery of earth-like planets.
是的  就是这时候
This is it. This is the moment
当我们人类将要发现第一批类地球的时候
When we humans are going to find the first earths,
理解它们  明白它们是多么普通
understand them, understand how common they are.
但是我们想走得更远
But we'd like to go farther.
太空望远镜和星际探测器最终
Ultimately, space telescopes and interstellar probes
不仅会发现新的行星
could actually go beyond discovering new planets
并找到它们的居民
and discover their inhabitants.
如果我们可以在银河系的其他地方找到生命
If we could find indigenous life elsewhere in our galaxy
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
美国加州大学伯克利分校
跟地球上的生命无关
that's really quite independent of that on earth,
那将会是人类历史上最伟大的发现之一
it would be one of the greatest discoveries in the history of humans.
另一个世界的生命也许距离我们几千光年
Life on other worlds could be thousands of light-years away,
但是在地球周围不断地出现决定性的线索
but critical clues are constantly circling the earth.
它们是彗星
They are comets,
科学家们正在捕捉它们的尘状拖尾
And scientists are capturing their dust trails
并发射神风特攻队探测器探查它们冰封的秘密
and launching Kamikaze probes to extract their icy secrets.
空间探测器大大地推进了
Space probes have pushed
我们对于宇宙的知识
the boundary of our knowledge of the cosmos.
当人类进入了星际探索的崭新的黄金期
As humanity enters a new golden age for interstellar exploration,
一些探测器不断地揭露地球附近的秘密
some probes are uncovering secrets much closer to home.
我们的太阳系充满着
Our solar system is full of
迅速移动的碎片和微粒
fast-moving debris and particles,
包括冰和星尘形成的巨大球体  彗星
including the giant balls of ice and dust called comets.
彗星就像时代文物密藏器
Comets are like time capsules.
艾米·美因茨
美国宇航局喷气推进实验室
它们冻结了从四十五亿年前
They're frozen remnants left over from when
太阳系第一次形成留下的残余物
our solar system first formed 4 1/2 billion years ago.
我们通过宇宙飞船研究彗星
We've had great success studying comets
而取得了巨大的成功
with spacecraft.
深度撞击飞船的发射的确撞入了一颗彗星
The Deep Impact mission actually slammed into a comet
录像记载了整个事件过程
and recorded the whole event on video.
2005年7月3日
July 3, 2005,
美国航天局的深度撞击一号空间探测器
NASA's Deep Impact 1 space probe
进入了彗星坦普尔1号的活动范围
creeps within range of the comet Tempel 1.
当彗星以大约每小时两万三千英里的速度
As the comet hurtles forward
冲过来
at about 23,000 miles per hour,
探测器直接向这颗四英里宽的
the probe launches an impactor satellite directly into the path
彗星的轨道发射了一颗撞击卫星
of the four-mile-wide comet.
事实上它撞向了彗星
What it actually did is it impacted the comet
特拉维斯·S·泰勒
物理学家
飞溅出一片尘云
and caused a dust cloud to fly out of it,
因为我们想看看彗星内部是什么
Because the trick was, we wanted to see what was inside the comet,
彗星是由什么东西构成的
what is the comet really made of.
这次撞击使坦普尔1号
The impact ejects
喷射出一千一百万磅冰
some 11 million pounds of ice
和累计五千五百万磅的星尘
and up to 55 million pounds of dust from Tempel 1.
这是第一次科学家们可以近距离地
It's the first time scientists are able to record
记录和研究彗星物质
and study cometary material up close.
关于彗星到底是什么  它揭示了很多
And it reveals much about what a comet really is.
美国宇航局视频  深度空间1
空间探测器已经告诉我们
The space probes have told us
彗星不是一个满是星尘的雪球
that a comet is more like a frozen watermelon
而且更像一个冰冻西瓜
than it is a dirty snowball.
原来它有一层的相当坚实的
There turns out to be a really hard compacted layer of ice
混着尘埃的冰层
with dust mixed in with it,
泥泞的满是星尘的雪球状物位于内部
And then the slushy dirty snowball stuff is on the inside.
就像个有层外皮  内部有瓤的西瓜
It's kinda got a rind and then the watermelony stuff on the inside.
当它沿着轨道越来越靠近太阳  开始升温
And as it gets closer to the sun on its orbit, it heats up,
内部的水变成蒸汽喷出来
And then the water on the inside turns into steam and squirts out.
因此我们看到了尘状拖尾
And that's why we see the dust trails
和彗星的间歇喷泉
and the geysers squirting out of the comet.
样本1  深度撞击  坑位
深度撞击探测器送回了令人炫目的图像
The Deep Impact probe returns stunning images,
但是它没有真正抓住彗尾
But it doesn't actually catch a comet by the tail.
那是名叫星尘的彗星探测器的任务
That's a job for the comet probe called Stardust.
2004年
In 2004,
星尘号在距彗星怀尔德2号149英里处航行
Stardust cruises within 149 miles of comet Wild 2.
星尘号宇宙飞船就这样
So the Stardust spacecraft
慢慢飞过彗尾
literally flew through the tail of a comet
凯文·P·格拉齐尔
美国宇航局喷气推进实验室
收集相关物质
to collect that material
就是从彗星表面挣脱的气体
That's being degassed off the surface of a comet.
为了捕获这些宝贵的粒子
To capture the precious particles,
星尘号部署了一个收集器
Stardust deploys a collector
跟网球拍的尺寸和形状差不多
about the size and shape of a tennis racquet.
内部是一个多孔的海绵状胶体
Inside is a porous, sponge-like gel.
彗星飞过的时候
As the comet flies past,
粒子以大约六倍于
the particles embed themselves in the gel,
来福枪子弹的速度嵌入胶体中
at about six times the speed of a rifle bullet.
我们获得的物质基本上可以算是
We're literally getting the material out of which
构成彗星的物质  当然也是构成
the comets were made and surely the material
杰佛里·马尔西
美国加州大学伯克利分校
行星  小行星
out of which the planets, the asteroids,
太阳系中的卫星的物质
the moons in our solar system were also made.
我们正在捕获的几乎是最原始的物质
We're getting nearly the pristine material,
构成和建造我们太阳系的
the building blocks of which our solar system
基本成分
is composed and was built.
采集好物质后
Once the material is gathered,
那个收集器就会被存放在一个密封舱中
the collector is stowed in a capsule.
2006年1月15日
And on January 15, 2006,
珍贵的样品飞回到了地球
the precious samples plummet back to earth.
嵌入在胶体内的首先被发现的秘密
Among the first secrets discovered embedded in the gel
是甘氨酸分子  有机生命用来合成蛋白质的
are glycine molecules, an amino acid used by living orgasms
必需氨基酸  维持生命的必需的基本物质
to make proteins, a fundamental requirement for sustaining life.
有些人推测说
And there are some folks who suggest
彗星上也许有生物学有机体
that perhaps there could be biological organisms
被冷冻在冰中
trapped in the ices on these comets.
甚至会有类似流感病毒之类的物质
Even, like, flu viruses or something could be there.
星尘号没有捕获到任何病毒
Stardust didn't capture any viruses,
但是它的发现支持了那种理论
But its discoveries support the theory
认为构成人类的生命基本物质
that the very building blocks of the human race
可能形成于太空  并且在很久以前
could have formed in space and they were long ago
被彗星或陨石传送到地球
delivered to the earth by meteorites or comets.
胶体内更多的秘密被发现
An even more bizarre secret is discovered trapped in the gel,
甚至飞得最远的空间探测器都还没有
particles that even the farthest-reaching space probes
收集到的粒子  真正来自其他太阳的物质
haven't yet gathered: the actual material from other suns.
我相信它们已经找到了一些尘粒
I believe they have found some dust particles
好像是来自于太阳系外  来自其他恒星
that appear to come from outside our solar system, from other stars,
这些尘粒从那些恒星流出来
Because they have solar winds themselves,
因为它们有自己的太阳风
the dust particles are flowing away from those stars
其中的一些正好进入了太阳系
And some of them happen to come into our solar system
被星尘探测器捕获
and they get captured by the Stardust probe.
我们第一次捕获了
We have captured for the first time,
来自其他恒星的星尘
literally, stardust from other stars.
太神奇了  太神奇了
That's amazing. That's amazing.
来自怀尔德2号彗星的星尘一直被研究至今
The stardust analysis from Comet Wild 2 continues to this day
可以帮助我们更深刻地理解
and could yield even more insight into the origins
我们这个宇宙小角落的起源
of our tiny corner of the universe.
如果你想知道我们的太阳和行星是如何形成的
If you want to understand how our sun and planet were formed,
劳拉·丹利
葛瑞菲斯天文台
你就得理解我们是由哪些物质构成的
you need to understand the material out of which we were formed.
但是想更好的了解宇宙
But a better understanding of our universe
不应从遥远的恒星微粒着手
may come not from particles from distant suns,
而应从离我们最近的恒星开始
But from the star closest to our home.
一艘探测器正等待发射  完成一次人类从未设想过的
A revolutionary probe is awaiting a launch date to fly headlong
革命性探索  飞往太阳系最热的区域
into the hottest region that man has ever attempted to explore.
现在  空间探测器穿梭翱翔于银河中
Space probes now soar through the galaxy
探寻火星  金星  外太空巨星
to explore the mysteries of Mars, Venus, the outer giants,
遥远的外部行星甚至最远的那些星球的秘密
the distant exoplanets and the farthest stars.
可我们自己星系的太阳仍有尚未解开的谜题
But our own home star still has its unsolved mysteries.
这很快就会不同了
That's about to change.
之前的观测只覆盖了一些小区域  而不是整个太阳
Previously we looked at small areas, not the whole disk
托德·霍克斯马
斯坦福大学
或者说我们的观测时间有漏洞  经常三天打鱼
or we've had gaps in our coverage where we've looked for a day
两天晒网
or we've not looked for a day,
或者只花一天中的部分时间观测  而没有持续观测
we've looked for part of day, but not the whole time.
这是我们第一次有机会  全面观测太阳
So this is really our first chance to look at the sun as a whole star.
2010年2月11日
一艘高科技太阳探测器驶抵太空    准备就绪
A high-tech solar probe arrives in space, locked and loaded.
它的任务是  对太阳进行全天候高清彩色观测
Its mission: watch the sun 24/7 in high-definition color
并通过一兆的带宽向地球传输图片
and transmit mega broadband images back to earth.
太阳动力学观测卫星
The solar dynamics observatory
拍摄的太阳照片  具有极高的分辨率
takes images of the sun in very high resolution,
劳拉·丹利
格里费斯天文台
极高的清晰度  和各种波长
high definition, in many wavelengths,
可以这么说  它在拍摄太阳的电影
and essentially, it takes movies of the sun.
它配备了四架高清望远镜
Using four HD telescopes,
SDO发射的探测器架起一条永不间断的高清信道
the SDO transmits an unblinking hi-def-like channel to earth,
它向地球上载的科学数据
uploading 50 times more science data
是NASA历史上其它探测任务获得数据的五十多倍
than any probe mission in NASA history.
能看到第一手图像资料  真是让人兴奋
It was really exciting to look at some of the first images.
我们看到的是  一个地方的细微特征
What we saw was very small features in one place
对其它地方造成了重大影响
having a big effect someplace else.
因此  我们可以观察到一些发生在
So we could see something near the center of the disk,
接近太阳系  太阳中心的现象与
center of the sun, and you could see the connection
发生在十万二十万英里之外的现象之间的联系
between that and what was happening 100,000, 200,000 miles away.
高等光学仪器通过10种不同波长的光
The advanced optics watched the sun in 10 different
观测太阳  其中包括远紫外线
light wavelengths, including the extreme ultraviolet.
这种波长的光极度有害
This wavelength is so deadly
要是没有地球上空大气层的过滤它
that without earth's upper atmosphere to filter it,
人在海边晒一天就足以致命
a day at the beach would be fatal.
我们最终的目标是观察太阳内部
Our eventual goal is to look inside the sun,
看清在它表面之下  进行着怎样的活动
to see what's happening below the surface:
比如太阳内部有怎样的流动  怎样的运动
what the currents are, what the motions are,
以及它们是如何联系在一起  组成一幅波澜壮阔的画面
and how that all ties together in a big picture.
SDO将被用做探测器  日震学磁像仪
The SDO will activate a sensor, the helioseismic magnetic imager,
SDO 日震与磁成像仪
它能透过太阳炙热的表面  探测下面的事物
that can see through the scorching solar surface.
日震与磁成像仪
The helioseismic and magnetic imager:
运用声波探测太阳的内部
we're using sound waves to probe inside.
就像我们探测地震时用的方法
Just like we do in a seismic way for earthquakes,
我们通过太阳内部的声波
we can use sound waves inside the sun to look and see
了解内部发生的一切
what's happening inside.
我们尝试通过检测声波反射出太阳表面时的振动
So we look at the vibrations as they bounce off the surface
弄清太阳里正发生的一切
and then try and figure out what's happening inside the sun.
科学家们最热切想解开的
It's this inner core, the solar dynamo,
是太阳的发动机  太阳内核的秘密
that scientists most want to demystify.
高能物质从这里
From here come the unpredictable,
毫无预兆地喷涌而出
violent eruptions of high-energy material
威胁着地球
that can threaten the earth.
这些物质都带着电荷
So, that material is charged,
常常形成所谓的日冕物质抛射
often in the form of what's called a coronal mass ejection.
克利福德·约翰逊
南加利福尼亚大学
这是大量以带电粒子形态存在的物质
It's a huge amount of material in the form of charged particles.
那些带电粒子抵达地球
Those charged particles arrive here at earth
与地磁场相互作用
and interact with our magnetic field.
如果能靠得足够近  对这种活动
If you can get close enough to do direct measurements
进行直接的测量
on that sort of activity,
我们就能更好理解这些现象的原理
we'd better understand how those processes work.
接近行星体
Getting close to planetary bodies
是半个世纪以来空间探测器一直在进行的工作
is something space probes have been doing for half a century.
可要让探测器接近太阳  无异于自杀
But getting a probe close to the sun is a suicide mission.
真是这样的吗
Or is it?
预计在2015年
Scheduled for launch in 2015,
太阳探测器+
Solar Probe Plus will fly
将径直飞入太阳两百万度的日冕  并免于毁灭
directly into the sun's 2-million-degree corona and survive.
太阳探测器+将到达离太阳很近的位置
Solar Probe Plus will get very close to the sun,
艾力克斯·菲利潘科
美国加州大学伯克利分校
大概在八或九个太阳半径之内
within eight or nine solar radii from the sun.
作为对比
Now, for comparison,
地球离太阳中心有两百个太阳半径的距离
the earth is 200 solar radii from the center of the sun.
这就意味着   太阳探测器+会被日冕浸没
So, Solar Probe Plus is gonna be immersed within the corona.
日冕是这个我们称之为太阳的恒星  神秘的组成部分
The corona is a mysterious part of the star we call the sun.
尽管日冕离日核较远
Though farther from the sun's core,
但实际上  它比太阳表面的温度高
it's actually hotter than the sun's surface.
可要是一个人能到达那的话
But if a human were to somehow get there,
那的寒冷会让他们大吃一惊
they'd get a frigid surprise.
日冕的温度非常高  有几百万度
The solar corona is very hot, millions of degrees in temperature.
也就是说  粒子在飞速运动
That means the particles are moving around very, very rapidly.
于是你会想  要是陷入日冕
So you might think that if you were immersed in the corona,
就会被烧焦
you'd get burned.
可是那的粒子的数量极少
But there are so few particles,
因此  通过碰撞转移到体内的总能量
that the total amount of energy being transferred to a body
比辐射入体内的总能量少
is less than the amount of energy being radiated.
实际上  如果有一块性能优异的隔热板
So, in fact, you would freeze if you were immersed
能保护你避免太阳的照射
in the solar corona, as long as you had a good heat shield
那么一进入日冕区域  你就会冻僵
protecting you from the disk of the sun.
太阳探测器+会装备上
Solar Probe Plus will come equipped
一块轻型泡沫碳隔热板
with a lightweight carbon-foam heat shield,
使得探测器不管是在热浪
allowing it to survive the massive heat,
还是冻结效应的影响下  都能以接近室温的温度运行
the freezing effect, and even operate near room temperature.
太阳探测器+完成任务之时
When it completes its mission, Solar Probe Plus
将向我们展现太阳磁场的构造
will reveal the structure of the sun's magnetic Fields
探索日冕的高温来源
and explore the flow of solar energy
并且孕育了地球生命的太阳能量流动
that heats the sun's corona and makes life on our planet possible.
我们必须记住  太阳是离我们最近的恒星
It's important to remember that the sun is the nearest star.
说真的  研究太阳
So really, it's important to study the sun
在我们对宇宙所有恒星的研究事业中
as part of the entire enterprise
是一个意义重大的环节
of studying all the stars in the universe.
最终  空间探测器带来的知识将远不止于太阳
Ultimately, space probes will bring us knowledge far beyond the sun
而是深入我们星系的偏远地带
and into the distant parts of our galaxy,
在那里  数十亿太阳在燃烧
where billions of other suns burn and potentially,
也许  还有几颗蓝色的星球等待着人们去探索
a few blue planets await future human explorers.
为了揭开宇宙最神奇的秘密
To learn some of the most amazing secrets about our universe,
艾米·美因茨
美国国家宇航局/喷气推进实验室
我们需要航天器的帮助  因为它们可以前往观测
we need spacecraft because they can go places
那些我们在地球上到达不了  观测不到的地方
and see things that we could never do from here on earth.
我们向宇宙发射探测器  还出于一个更深层的原因
There's a deeper reason that we send probes out into space.
人类骨子里流淌着求知与发现的血液
We humans have it in our DNA to be curious and to explore.
杰佛里·马尔西
美国加州大学伯克利分校
当然了  我们向太空
and of course, probes that we send into space,
向行星  以及最终向恒星发射的探测器
to the planets, and ultimately to the stars,
代表着一颗我们向宇宙移民的心
represent our migration into the cosmos.
人类作为一个整体
It is almost certainly our destiny as a species
几乎注定要驶出地球  飞入银河系
to crawl off the planet earth and out into our galaxy
走向宇宙
and the universe as a whole.
到那一天
Until that day,
空间探测器将会继续向我们呈现宇宙的奇观
space probes will continue to peel back the wonders of the cosmos,
这些机器承载着人类探索恒星的梦想
and the universe will continue to give up her secrets,
宇宙也将继续向我们展现她的秘密
as these robotic avatars persue humanity's quest for the stars.